[opening theme music playing]
IN A DUSTY UNIVERSE
- [light switch clicks]
- Uh--
Well, you've got some stuff in here.
You made it sound like all you had
was four walls and a door.
Yeah. The more you own,
the more it owns you.
[Jack chuckles]
High School Proficiency exam?
[Legoshi] Yeah. [inhales]
If I want to work at the insect museum,
I need a high school diploma.
Should've thought about that
before I dropped out.
[Jack] You're trying to get a job there?
Oh, well... [chuckles]
...it's just a dream, for now.
Okay, a dream.
Yeah, I get it.
Gotta have those.
Hey, full moon's on its way.
Sometimes when there's a full moon out,
Kolo and I see
who has the best pretend howl.
[Legoshi]
Howling's banned on campus, right?
Well, we just pretend.
We're real quiet about it.
Knowing your voice could reach out
into the night sure is a comfort.
[Legoshi]
His tail's not wagging.
[Jack] I bet you've got
a great howl, Legoshi.
- Hey, Jack?
- [Jack] Hmm?
Is everything all right?
You seem... a little off.
Well, I...
I guess it's just these advanced classes,
they're kinda wearing me out.
These classes, are they that tough?
Well, maybe?
Not tough.
Mm. More like a unique experience.
Unique, how?
One of the classes, everyone's dogs.
Everyone?
Makes sense if you think about it.
I mean, with us dogs,
we were specifically bred
to have advanced intelligence.
So you're saying that dogs
are really good at studying?
[Jack] Mmm.
It also means we're cool under pressure.
We don't let our emotions
get the better of us.
END OF THE FIRST CARNIVORE-HERBIVORE WAR
In the advanced courses,
they make us study things
that are not taught in regular classes.
Like which species drove another species
to extinction...
and which species preyed on which.
[inhales] And we sit there,
just copying it all into our notebooks.
Lapping up these facts,
like nothing even happened.
And when class is over,
we smile and wave like it's no big deal.
Like we're just robots
doing what we're programmed to do.
If you were in this class,
I don't think you'd have a very good time.
Doesn't seem you're having
a good time, though.
If that's the case,
why don't I drop the class?
Why don't I feel disgusted?
Is it because I'm a dog?
Born to be calm and rational?
Guess that's my nature.
I've got this pit in my stomach.
Like, what if I'm actually
just numb on the inside?
If I could at least cry,
that would be something.
At least I could feel.
So that's why you were carrying this?
Uh...
Yeah.
I use onions.
This is one way I can force myself to cry.
Huh?
- Let me show you what I mean.
- Um...
This is my salvation.
Hold on a sec!
- [Jack grunts]
- Whoa, Jack, hey!
[crying] I can't stand myself.
Being a Labrador!
If all dogs are like this,
we'll end up dictators! [grunts]
I'm not sure about that.
I, uh, I wouldn't...
[crying] We're made to be obedient.
If we were told to go on a killing spree,
then that's what we'd do!
Dogs are terrifying.
And I'm a dog!
[gasps] Jack, come on!
You're more than just your species.
You feel the way you do
because you're Jack.
Before anything, you're Jack!
[crying]
How do you know what I am?
How can you really know what's inside?
[soft music playing]
Because we grew up together.
[sobbing softly]
Does that make sense?
[Jack]
Together?
I don't know.
You left me behind
and grew up on your own.
Free to do what you wanted.
I can't relate to that.
Come on.
Let's cheer you up.
How about we get
that tail wagging again, Jack?
[Jack sniffles]
[munching]
[gasps] You idiot! Are you crazy?
You can't eat an onion!
You think I'll be obedient
just because I'm a dog?
What are you saying, do you wanna die?
Even Labradors need to rebel sometimes!
[choking]
Throw it up! Hear me?
[gagging]
Spit it all out!
[Jack gagging]
[Jack] I can feel Legoshi's sharp claws
hitting the back of my throat.
It hurts a lot.
This is who he is.
Nothing's changed.
He's always been this way.
[gagging]
[Jack breathing heavily]
[Legoshi]
Sorry, bud.
Onions kill canines.
That would have been it.
I need you to take care of yourself.
Because my hope is,
one day when we're old,
you and I will still be
laughing and crying together.
Just like we did today.
That's quite the dream, you mangy wolf.
Because you're a real pain in the tail.
[howling in distance]
[Jack]
Hmm?
[howling continues]
[chuckles]
[howls]
Legoshi! [chuckles]
[Legoshi howling]
[woman vocalizing]
Melda?
I'm sorry, but I'm at a loss.
The drug that was unveiled
at the masquerade party,
we know the Shishigumi
transported it from here.
You don't say!
What kind of drug is this?
That's what I'm asking you.
Is that what this is?
- Oh, what an imagination.
- [sniffs]
That's my top-notch Kopi Luwak.
You know there are some types of foods,
those produced by animals,
like eggs or milk,
that can be satisfying in a way
that's similar to meat,
just like this Kopi Luwak.
[Yahya grunting]
[exhales, sniffles]
[Deshico] Hmm.
Why would it affect an herbivore?
Your first time trying Kopi Luwak?
Yeah.
You know, it's carnivores
that usually react that way.
[Yahya] Is it because my carrots
absorbed meat nutrients?
Could it be possible that... you're mixed?
What makes you say that?
It makes some sense.
First of all,
there's your exceptional decisiveness.
And when approaching a situation,
you're passionately all-in.
And you don't hesitate to use violence.
You abhor criticism,
and your self-confidence
borders on arrogance.
[Yahya chuckles]
Of course, these traits don't necessarily
confirm your hybrid nature.
However, you do remind me
of a hybrid specimen I studied.
You mean Melon?
Can't say.
As a research institute,
we have strict rules of confidentiality.
How convenient.
Did you write down a mixed species'
weakness in your research notes?
[chuckles]
You're quite the blunt instrument.
- I'm not one for small talk.
- I've noticed.
Well, the academic consensus seems to be...
that mixed species
quite often lack a strong appetite.
And they display
a weaker than normal sex drive.
Those sound like an advantage
in this day and age.
Possibly, but I imagine
it's still difficult.
Never feeling satisfied
no matter what they eat?
[Yahya] "Never feeling satisfied
no matter what they eat"?
- [panting]
- [boy 1] You're not a real herbivore!
- Look at him run!
- [boy 2] Nowhere to hide!
[boy 1] Do it! Jump!
There's no reality
where you could become a professor.
You're not a real herbivore,
you half-breed.
[all mocking]
Being part feline,
I'm sure you'll land on your feet.
[screams]
[thuds]
Let's find a bag to put this evidence in.
- Uh, yeah.
- [thunder rumbles]
Hmm.
Close the windows, if you don't mind.
COEXISTENCE THEORY
[straining]
- So, Haru...
- Yes?
You were telling me,
you've been in a situation
where your life was in danger.
Well, being a rabbit,
it's not that unusual.
Are you afraid of being around carnivores?
Um... If you're afraid all the time,
it makes it hard to get
to know other species, right?
That'd be scary too.
As scary as being eaten?
Yeah, I think so. Whoa!
[grunts] Oh.
I'm all right, it's... [groans]
If you stick with that mindset
your whole life,
- someday you may actually get eaten.
- [groaning]
If I have to live in the company of death,
I prefer to focus on love.
[thunder rumbling]
Wow, it's really coming down!
[Melon] Inside that fragile little body
clinging to every heartbeat...
there's a universe of thoughts
and ideas stirring within her.
[laughs]
This rain is crazy!
[Melon] I do wonder...
Could I taste those thoughts and emotions?
Are they in her blood and flesh?
[salivates]
I think...
I wanna find out.
[gasps]
[Haru]
I know this fear. I've felt it.
[exclaims]
Just stop it!
What's your species, Professor?
[Melon]
Huh?
Uh, well, the way you were holding me
wasn't romantic.
It was almost like
how a carnivore catches an herbivore
right before they, uh...
But, I... I always need to be careful
because I'm a rabbit,
but it doesn't help
that I've had a few close calls.
Uh, it's just... I'm just rambling.
- [Haru chuckles nervously]
- [Melon] Not to worry.
As you can see, I'm a gazelle.
Oh, uh, yes, of course you are. [chuckles]
A gazelle, yes.
Uh, no way you're a carnivore, but, um...
Uh, Professor...
When you grabbed me,
was that you trying to make a move?
- [thunder rumbles]
- [chuckles nervously]
I'm flattered, but, uh, there's a boy
I kind of like right now and, um...
I was kind of a late bloomer
with dating,
so I'm not really used
to how it all works.
- [gasps]
- [clicking]
- [thunder crashes]
- [Melon groans]
[Melon laughing]
[groans]
I knew it. [inhales]
First time something like this
has happened. [inhales sharply]
The pain isn't that bad... right now.
[inhales sharply]
The pain in my heart might be worse.
- [Melon inhales]
- [Haru shudders]
[Melon] This has certainly
gotten complicated. [chuckles]
Hasn't it?
[thunder crashes]
[Legoshi]
Appreciate your business.
Hey, uh, before you go.
You guys have a secret menu, right?
What? I don't know anything about that.
Come on, you don't have to play dumb.
I want something exotic.
Udon with meat.
We don't have anything like that.
The fact that you're acting like this
tells me you do.
Ugh. Gotta go.
[male bear]
He said no.
I'll buy some lamb
at the black market tomorrow.
[female bear] Let's do that.
Ooh, we can find a good meat udon recipe!
[Legoshi] Am I being extreme?
It does seem to make 'em happy.
[Yahya]
I've seen that troubled face before.
Hm? Oh.
Mr. Yahya! Hey.
You're walking on that leg just fine.
So, did you find Melon?
[Legoshi]
Uh, well, uh...
For starters, how about giving back
that mask you borrowed?
Uh... Sorry, sir.
I ended up dropping it into the sea.
Or, actually, I was dropped.
So you did meet Melon?
Very brave.
You said you were done
with the Melon situation.
Did something else come up?
Tell me more about this conversation
you had with Melon.
It was pretty terrible.
I was too naive.
Figured as much.
True evil is real, and it's him.
It was terrifying.
Man, I was so scared.
Guess I still am.
So even the invincible Legoshi
gets scared?
[groans softly]
He enjoyed watching me die.
In my head, I pictured flames.
This huge fire inside.
And I know those flames.
Whenever I ate meat,
when I ended up in a fight...
I saw those flames inside.
What if I've got a Melon inside me?
That's what... That's what I'm afraid of.
[Yahya] So this is what makes
Melon so terrifying.
I don't want to face him.
I see.
I'm sorry about losing the mask,
but I need to go.
They'll dock my pay if I take too long.
Yeah. Do what you gotta do.
[Legoshi] Will I always fear that beast
that lives inside me?
[faint humming]
Huh?
[panting]
[chuckles]
I was getting pretty tired of waiting
for the lone wolf to return.
[chuckles]
[Haru]
All right, coming in.
- Hey, look how cozy this is.
- Mmm.
Oh, the mint plant is really healthy,
look at you!
[Legoshi] Interesting.
I've got a great sense of smell.
Another male. I can smell him on her!
Who the hell was he?
[Haru]
I'll bring you some fertilizer.
[Legoshi] Ugh!
The rain's messing up the scent!
Hey, Legoshi?
Huh?
Trains are done for the night.
Can I just stay here?
Oh. Stay?
Overnight?
What?
[chuckles] Don't worry.
I even brought my own toothbrush.
- Uh...
- See?
Oh. [chuckling]
[Haru sipping]
Mm. This tea is so yummy!
[Legoshi] Mmm.
- Haru, uh...
- Hm?
Well, um...
[laughs nervously]
Have... Have you been enjoying yourself?
Uh, on campus, I mean.
Is there something you wanna talk about?
No! Uh, I was just making conversation.
And is that why your tail's all raised?
Oh. [chuckles] Come on.
I was just thinking...
that schools have a lot
of guys and girls interacting and...
[Haru] Legoshi!
What do you think this is?
You think you can lock a girl down
without even dangling a carrot?
Exactly how long am I supposed
to wait for even a kiss?
Hey now, slow down!
What about the risks?
Physically, socially, and economically...
[sighs] You're not as smart
as you think you are.
Hey, now.
And, about that, with the physical stuff...
We don't know, do we?
Huh?
We have no idea how it would work,
because you literally
haven't done anything yet.
Huh?
How will we ever know
if you don't show me?
[Legoshi]
Oh, this is intense.
Are you serious?
- Don't I look serious?
- Uh...
Show me, Legoshi. Give it to me!
- You can eat me any time.
- Uh...
And there's not a damn thing
I can do about it!
So, for tonight,
just let me have a taste of you.
[groaning]
[unzipping]
[Legoshi] Haru,
since the day I fell in love with you,
something's always been
in the back of my mind.
How, if I were a female rabbit
and you were a male wolf...
How, if you held me
or if you ate me...
I'd be happy. Either way.
[Haru sighs]
I'm really sorry.
I'm not normally like this.
What?
Why would you think you have to apologize?
I'm really happy you opened up to me.
I wasn't sure you had it in you.
[Legoshi]
Sitting here in this sparse room,
her fur and mine
float in the air, sparkling,
making everything feel... strangely unreal.
Forget the drama
of mixed species marriage.
Forget society's opinions.
If this room could be our own universe,
and all that existed
was just the two of us,
then here, I could--
Hey, how'd you get that?
Hm? What? Oh.
- And how'd that happen?
- [laughs] I fell down.
Like I haven't heard that lie
from a guy before.
And that's not the only injury you have.
Oh. [chuckles]
Oh, Legoshi, my word.
I guess, when all is said and done,
you're a true carnivore.
You're a wolf.
You're born with that instinct.
I mean, violence and danger
is part of who you are.
- Mm.
- It is what it is.
However, I'm gonna bet
you're more mature than that!
[Legoshi grunts]
Hey, how about from now on,
I help you live your life
more like an adult.
Not all at once.
Little by little. Yeah?
I think I'd like that.
All right then.
The parts of us we haven't shared,
we'll show them to each other
a bit at a time.
[Legoshi chuckles] I'm pretty sure
you saw more than a bit tonight.
[Haru laughs] You think so?
[softly] Thump, thump, thump...
It's the sound of you living.
Is that also a part you don't know?
Mm-mm.
It's the part I know best.
[groans softly]
[smacks lips]
Mmm.
Haru?
[groans]
[dramatic music playing]
[closing song playing]